adsrsounds.com 2019-04-01

# Privacy Statement – ADSR

Updated May 2018

We respect privacy and your rights to control your personal data. Our principle guidelines are simple. We will be clear about the data we collect and why. Your data is reverently protected by us. We do not and will not sell your data to third parties.

The prime purpose of collecting your data is to help you make better music.

This Privacy Statement (the ‘Statement’) explains the personal information we collect from you, either directly or indirectly, and how we will use it. Personal information is any information that can be used to identify you or that we can link to you. The Statement also elaborates on the choices you can make about the data we collect, and how you can control these decisions. It applies to all products offered by ADSR (‘ADSR Product(s)’) including our subscription service on adsrsounds.com. It also applies to any ADSR-controlled websites, as well as other offline interactions, such as attending an ADSR event (collectively referred to as, ‘Services’). Please read this Statement carefully to understand how ADSR may collect, use and share your personal information. The terms ‘we’, ‘us’, or ‘ADSR’ are each intended as reference to ADSR Ltd.

#### The Types of Personal Information We Collect

We may collect your personal data in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when you visit our Site, register on the Site, subscribe to our newsletter, fill out a form, or in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available. We may collect the following types of information about you on our Website

► **Registration and Contact Information:**

As appropriate and depending on the Services you would like to use, Customers and Visitors may be asked to provide us with full name, username, email, address, credit card, phone number or billing information.

► **Payment Information:**

When you purchase the Services, we will also collect transaction information, which may include your credit card information, billing and mailing address, and other payment-related information. Please note that all transactions are processed through a gateway provider and your credit card details are not stored or processed on our servers.

► **Technical, Usage and Location Information:**

We automatically collect information on how you interact with the Site, such as the IP address from which you access the Site, date and time, information about your browser, operating system and computer or device, pages viewed and items clicked. We may also collect location information, including location information automatically provided by your computer or device. We use cookies and similar technologies to collect some of this information and persist your login to our Site.

► **Third Party Platforms:**

We may collect information when you interact with our advertisements and other content on third-party sites or platforms, such as social networking sites. This may include information such as Facebook Likes, profile information gathered from social networking sites during signup or the fact that you viewed or interacted with our content.

► **Other Information:**

We may collect other information from you that is not specifically listed here. We may use any such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy or as otherwise permitted by you.

► **Information of children:**

ADSR does not target and is not intended to attract children under the age of sixteen. Although visitors of all ages may navigate through our website, we do not knowingly collect or request personal information from those under the age of sixteen without parental consent. If, following a notification from a parent, guardian or discovery by other means, a child under sixteen has been improperly registered on our site by using false information, we will cancel the child’s account and delete the child’s personal information from our records.

#### Customer Interactions with ADSR

To make the information in this Statement easy to understand, we have highlighted different occasions when ADSR could potentially collect personal information from customers. The customer interactions with ADSR are broken down into the following segments:

► **Discovering ADSR & Browsing the Site**

As you gather more information about ADSR, you may virtually or physically visit a site that we own. Examples include browsing our website, watching a video on youtube, contacting our customer service representatives or physically attending ADSR-sponsored events. To learn more about ADSR Products, you may voluntarily provide personal information, such as your name and email address during these interactions. We may also collect information about you online via cookies or similar technologies when you visit our website.

**We collect:** name, email address, IP address, and information provided by cookies or similar technology.

**Why:** We use this information to share news about events and products offered by ADSR. Additionally, the IP address helps us to understand geographic information about our website visitors better, so that we can improve our website for everyone. It is our legitimate interest to process your personal data for these purposes.

► **Buying ADSR Products**

When you make a purchase from us, you will be asked to provide information so that we can complete your purchase. All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.

**We collect:** Full name, username, email, address, credit card, phone number or billing information.

**Why:** We use this information to complete your transaction, carry out any follow up with you about your purchase, help with any delivery issues, handle returns, and other issues related to the purchase of ADSR Products. Processing your personal data for this purpose is necessary for the performance of the agreement we have with you.

► **Registering an Account**

As part of registering an account on the site you will be asked to enter information such as a name and email address along with additional Custom Fields which include Location, software preferences and other identifiable fields that the user can choose to fill out. Registering an account is necessary to access certain products and features including streaming subscription, wish lists, order history and the ability to download purchased orders directly from the site.

**We collect:** full name, username, email, address, phone number or billing information your name, location data, your password and IP address. Please note, your password is stored using one-way hash, which means that it cannot be recovered (or disclosed) by anyone, including ADSR.

**Why:** We collect this information to help you gain access to ADSR Products securely (which helps prevent unauthorised access to your ADSR Products and subscriptions). This processing is necessary for the performance of the contract we have with you. We also use your email to send you ADSR-related notifications, such as promotional messages, software updates, information about ADSR Products and/or Services, and to share exciting ADSR news and Product offerings. It is our legitimate interest to process your personal data for these purposes.

► **Special Promotions**

ADSR regularly runs competitions and giveaways with our own products services and those from selected partners. (Collectively referred to as, Special Promotions). When you participate in a special promotion you may be asked to provide certain information such as name and email address along with other custom fields related to the terms of entry.

**We collect:** name, email address, IP address, and information provided by cookies or similar technology. Some Special Promotions may also require additional Custom Fields, which include Date of Birth (for Age Verification), geographic location and other identifiable fields that the user can choose to fill out.

**Why:** We collect this information to register your entry/s and organize fulfillment in the event that you are a winner or giveaway recipient. Winner/s information may be shared with our partners but only with your written consent and only for the purposes of fulfillment. Each competition we run on the site is governed by its own set of terms and conditions, which are set out clearly on the competition entry page. Winner details such as name may be published on our site and on ADSR-controlled social sites such as facebook and Instagram with their consent.

► **Getting Help from ADSR**

From time to time, you may decide to contact our Customer Care group for assistance with your ADSR Products. To be able to offer you the best service possible, we may collect certain data from you or your ADSR Products.

**We collect:** This may include contact information, such as your name, email address, phone number, social media identifiers (if you contact us using a social media channel), and the content of your chats and other communications with ADSR Customer Care. In certain situations, it is useful for the Customer Care team to have a ‘Diagnostic’ of your system. This is essentially a you provision of a technical system snapshot of all relevant information leading up to the incident and includes information such as Product configuration, error codes, device information (e.g. the operating system, and other relevant software information). Collecting the above described information is necessary to provide customer support.).

**Why:** We collect this information to give you the best and most efficient customer support possible. For instance, for customer inquiries and technical questions, we use contact information to respond to the customer in their preferred channel (phone, email, social). For technical problems, we use system diagnostic data to effectively troubleshoot the issue. For product returns and/or exchanges, we use contact information to ensure successful product receipt and/or delivery. Using these types of data is necessary to fulfill the agreement we have with you.

#### How We Use Personal Information

ADSR uses the data we collect to provide you with the Products and Services we offer, which includes using data to improve and personalise your experiences. We also use the data to communicate with you, for example, informing you about your account, new products or services available, security and other types of updates.  
ADSR uses the data for the following purposes:

  * Providing our Product Experience
  * Customer Support
  * Product Improvement
  * Security, Safety, and Dispute Resolution
  * Business Operations
  * Communication, Marketing and Advertising

► **Providing our Product Experience**

We use data to provide, operate, support and improve the ADSR Products and Services we offer to ensure our customers can buy watch and learn as effortlessly as possible. This processing is necessary for the performance of the agreement we have with you.

► **Customer Support**

We use data to respond to customer enquiries, diagnose Product problems, repair customers’ ADSR Products and provide other customer care and support services. This processing is necessary for the performance of the agreement we have with you, as well as to serve our legitimate interest.

► **Product Improvement**

We continually use data for research purposes and to develop and improve our ADSR Products and Services, including maintaining and improving the performance of our ADSR Products and Services, developing and adding new features or capabilities, such as using error reports to improve security features, using search queries and clicks to improve the relevance of search results and using usage data to determine what new features to prioritise. This processing is necessary to serve our legitimate interest.

► **Security, Safety and Dispute Resolution**

We use data to protect the security and safety of our ADSR Products and our customers, to detect and prevent fraud, to resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. This processing is necessary to serve our legitimate interest.

► **Business Operations**

We use data to develop aggregate analysis and business intelligence that enable us to operate, protect, make informed decisions, and report on the performance of our business. This processing is necessary to serve our legitimate interest.

► **Communication, Marketing and Advertising**

We use the data we collect to deliver and personalise our communications with you. For example, we may contact you by email or other means of electronic communication (including through the ADSR website) to inform you about new ADSR Products or Services, security or software updates, update you on a support issue, invite you to take part in a survey. This processing is necessary to serve our legitimate interest. We also use cookies and similar technologies to provide the most relevant ADSR advertising to you. For information about managing email subscriptions and promotional communications, please visit Your Rights and Choices.  
To give you a better understanding of the personal information we collect and use in different occasions you may interact with ADSR, please see the sections below.

#### How We May Share Personal Information

ADSR does not and will not sell personal information about our customers. We only disclose your data as described in this Statement. We may share information with the following types of third parties.

► **Third Party Vendors**

ADSR uses a variety of third-party vendors to carry out services like website management and hosting, online Product purchases and shipping, credit card processing and email communications. We only share your personal data as necessary. To complete a transaction, provide a Product or Service you have requested or authorised and only with vendors or agents working on our behalf for the purposes described in this Statement. In this case, your personal information will be shared with these agents or contractors but only for the purpose of performing services on behalf of ADSR and in accordance with this Statement. It is our legitimate interest to process your personal data for these purposes. For questions about third-party vendors, please send an email to [privacy@adsrsounds.com](mailto:privacy@adsrsounds.com)

► **Prize and Product Fulfillment**

We share information with ADSR-controlled affiliates and subsidiaries for business purposes, such as, internal administration, promoting ADSR Products and providing customers with our ADSR Products and Services. It is our legitimate interest to process your personal data for these purposes. If you purchase a third party’s product through our website or service, we may disclose your name and/or email address to that third party if such disclosure is required in order to allow you to obtain and use a licence key for that product from that third party; From time to time ADSR hold different promotions in the form of giveaways and competitions. Should you be a winner or recipient of a third party product, your personal information may be shared with these agents or contractors but only for the purpose of prize fulfillment and only the minimum information required.

► **Compelled Disclosure**

When legally required, strictly necessary for the performance of the services or to protect our rights, or the rights of our affiliates or users, we disclose your personal information to law enforcement authorities, investigative organisations, our affiliates or in legal proceedings.

► **Sale or Merger**

We may share your personal information in the event of a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets. Of course, we shall notify you via email and/or a prominent notice on our website and inform you of your rights.

► **Sharing and Disclosure of Aggregate Data**

We share data in aggregate form and/or in a form which does not enable the recipient of such data to identify you, with third parties, for example, for industry analysis.  
Please note, our Products include links to Products or applications of third parties whose privacy practices may differ from ADSR. If you provide personal data to any of those third parties or their products, your data is governed by their privacy statements, and we encourage you to read these privacy statements carefully.  
When sharing data with third parties, your personal information may be transferred to countries where data protection laws may provide a lower standard of protection for your personal information than your country. We take great care in protecting your personal information and have put in place adequate mechanisms to protect it when it is transferred internationally. We will transfer your personal information in compliance with applicable data protection laws and will implement suitable safeguards to ensure that your personal information is adequately secured by any third party that will access your information (for instance, by using the Standard Contractual Clauses as approved by the European Commission). If you have questions or wish to obtain more information about the international transfer of your personal information or the implemented safeguards, please send us an email to [privacy@adsrsounds.com](mailto:privacy@adsrsounds.com).

#### The Legal Bases for Using Personal Information

There are different legal bases that we rely on to use your personal information, namely:

► **Performance of a contract**

The use of your personal information may be necessary to perform the agreement you have with us. For example, to complete your purchase of your ADSR Product, to register and maintain your account, to help with delivery issues, to handle returns, and to make sure that your ADSR Product performs its basic functions in a secure way or to respond to your requests.

► **Legitimate interests**

We may use your personal information for our legitimate interests. For example, we rely on our legitimate interest to analyse and improve our ADSR Products and Services and the content on our websites and app, to send you notifications about software updates or information about ADSR Products and Services or to use your personal information for administrative, fraud detection or legal purposes.

Where we process your personal information based on our legitimate interest and no opt-out mechanism is available to you (e.g. in your ADSR Account settings), you may exercise your right to object by sending an email to [privacy@adsrsounds.com](mailto:privacy@adsrsounds.com).

#### Security, Storage and Retention of Personal Information We Collect

► **Security**

ADSR is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. However, while we take reasonable precautions to guard the personal information we collect, no security system is impenetrable.

While no Service is completely secure, ADSR takes precautionary measures to help prevent information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorised access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. For example, we store the personal data you provide on computer systems that have limited access and that are in controlled facilities. We also ensure that our third-party data centre vendors provide adequate security measures. Additionally, your data is protected with encryption, such as Transport Layer Security (TLS), during transition over the Internet. Please note, your password is stored using one-way hash, which means that it cannot be recovered (or disclosed) by anyone, including ADSR, it can only be reset.

You can only access your ADSR account information and our service through the use of an individual user login and password. To protect the confidentiality of personal information, you must keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. Please notify us immediately if you believe your password has been misused. You should always log out and close your browser when you finish your session. Please note, we will never ask you to disclose your password in an unsolicited phone call or email.

ADSR uses Stripe to process our credit card payments and no credit card details are stored on our servers. Stripe has been audited by a PCI-certified auditor, and is certified to [PCI Service Provider Level 1](https://stripe.com/docs/security). This is the most stringent level of certification available.

If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [privacy@adsrsounds.com](mailto:privacy@adsrsounds.com).

► **Storage**

Personal data collected by ADSR may be stored and processed in your region, in the United States (for example, in our major data centres), or in any other country where ADSR or its affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers are located or maintain facilities. ADSR has put in place adequate mechanisms to protect personal information when it is transferred internationally, for example by using the Standard Contractual Clauses as approved by the European Commission.

► **Retention**

ADSR will retain your personal information for as long as we deem it necessary to enable you to use the website and your ADSR Product, to provide services to you, to comply with applicable laws (including those regarding document retention), resolve disputes with any parties and otherwise as necessary to allow us to conduct our business. All personal information we retain will be subject to this Privacy Statement and our internal retention guidelines. If you have a question about a specific retention period for certain types of personal information we process about you, please send an email to [privacy@adsrsounds.com](mailto:privacy@adsrsounds.com).

#### Your Rights and Choices

**YOUR RIGHTS**

We want you to be in control of how your personal information is used by us. Subject to local law, you can do this in the following ways:

  * you can ask us for a copy of the personal information we hold about you;
  * you can inform us of any changes to your personal information, or if you want us to correct any of the personal information we hold about you;
  * in certain situations, you can ask us to erase, block or restrict the personal information we hold about you, or object to particular ways in which we are using your personal information; and
  * in certain situations, you can also ask us to send the personal information you have given us to a third party.

Where we are using your personal information on the basis of your consent, you are entitled to withdraw that consent at any time. Moreover, where we process your personal information based on legitimate interest or the public interest, you have the right to object at any time to that use of your personal information.

We rely on you to ensure that your personal information is complete, accurate and up to date. Please do inform us promptly of any changes to or inaccuracies in your personal information by contacting [privacy@adsrsounds.com](mailto:privacy@adsrsounds.com).

We will respond to your request as soon as possible but certainly within 30 days. For more information about how you can control your Communication, Marketing and Advertising Preferences, please visit Your Choices sections below.

We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern you may have about our use of your personal information. If, however, you believe that we have not been able to assist with your complaint or concern, you may have the right to file a complaint with the data protection authority in your country (if one exists in your country) or supervisory authority.

**YOUR CHOICES**

► **ADSR Account**

If you wish to access, edit or remove profile information, change your password, close your account or request deletion of your personal data, you can do so by logging in to your ADSR account or ADSR app or sending an email to [privacy@adsrsounds.com](mailto:privacy@adsrsounds.com). If you cannot access certain personal information collected by ADSR, via your ADSR account you can always contact us by sending an email to [privacy@adsrsounds.com](mailto:privacy@adsrsounds.com). We will respond to any request to access or delete your personal data as soon as possible, certainly within 30 days.

► **Your Communication, Marketing and Advertising Preferences**

You can opt out of receiving direct marketing communications from ADSR by following the instructions included in every email sent to you via the “Unsubscribe” tab. You can also opt out of email subscriptions or in-app messaging by updating your Profile and Contact Options in your ADSR account. We respect your choice, and we will stop sending you promotional emails once you unsubscribe.

Please note, regardless of your communication settings, we will continue to communicate with you regarding changes to terms and conditions, policy updates, ADSR Product software updates, routine customer service messages such as information about current or past purchase, delivery of products, service interruptions, data breaches or other significant information about a Product you own, such as discontinuation of support or safety issues.

You can adjust the amount of interest based advertising you may receive by changing your cookie settings, changing your device settings, and/or opting out of certain advertising networks. If you have opted out of receiving emails from us, we will not use your email for interest-based advertising activities. For more information about our use of interest-based advertising, please visit Our Use of Cookies and Other Similar Technologies.

#### Our Use of Cookies and Other Similar Technologies

We use cookies and similar technologies like pixels, tags, web beacons, and other identifiers to help us personalise our website for you, remember your preferences, understand how users are using our website or app, and help customise our marketing offerings.

► Cookies

A cookie is a small data file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer when you visit a website. When you visit the website again, the cookie allows that site to recognise your browser. The length of time a cookie will stay on your computer or mobile device depends on whether it is a “persistent” or “session” cookie. ADSR uses both types of cookies. Session cookies will only stay on your device until you stop browsing. Persistent cookies stay on your computer or mobile device until they expire or are deleted. We use the following types of cookies on our website.

  * **Strictly necessary cookies.** These cookies are essential for you to browse our website and use its features. Without these cookies, services like shopping baskets cannot be provided.
  * **Performance cookies.** These cookies collect information about how you use our websites. This data may be used to help optimise our website and make it easier for you to navigate.
  * **Functional cookies.** These cookies allow our websites to remember choices you make while browsing and personalise your experience. We may store your geographic location in a cookie for instance, to ensure that we show you the website relevant to your area.
  * **Third Party cookies.** Third party cookies are those placed by websites and/or parties other than ADSR. These cookies may be used on our website to improve our products or services or to help us provide more relevant advertising. These cookies are subject to the respective privacy policies for these external services, for example, Facebook Data Use Policy.
  * **Analytics cookies.** We use analytics cookies, like those offered by Google Analytics, to help us understand things like how long a visitor stays on our website, what pages they find most useful, and how they arrived at ADSR.com. To learn more about Google Analytics and your data, visit this Google webpage.

► **How to control Cookie settings**

Most web browsers allow you to control cookies through their settings preferences. However, if you limit the ability of websites to set cookies, you may impair your overall user experience, as it will no longer be personalised to you. Some browsers offer a “Do Not Track” (“DNT”) signal where you can indicate your preference regarding tracking and cross-site tracking. Although we do not currently employ technology that recognises DNT signals, we will only process your personal data in accordance with this Statement. Below you can learn about how to control cookie settings on popular web browsers:  
• [Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en)  
• [Internet explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)  
• [Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/ph17191?locale=en_US)  
• [Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences)

► **Pixels**

In addition to cookies, we sometimes use small graphic images known as ‘pixels’ (also known as web beacons, clear GIFs, or pixel tags). We use pixels in our email communications to you (if you have selected to receive such communications) to help us to understand whether our email communication has been viewed. We also use third party pixels (such as those from Google, Facebook, and other advertising networks) to help us provide advertising that is relevant to your interests. Learn more about our advertising and marketing activities below.

► **Advertising and Modern Marketing Tools**

To help more people make music, we use several modern marketing tools in support of our advertising efforts.

ADSR may work with third-party advertisers that use cookies and similar technologies to provide more relevant advertising about ADSR Products and Services on our websites and across the internet. To provide this “interest-based advertising”, parties combine non-personal data about your online activities over time which helps cater advertising that we deliver to you. Examples of this may include an ADSR advertisement on a Facebook page, or a Google owned page such as a search results page or YouTube, or on a site within Google’s advertising network. We do not share your personal information as part of this process. Where necessary, we obtain your consent for this process. At all times, you can opt out of these personalised ads from third-party advertisers and ad networks who are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) or who follow the [Digital Advertising Alliance’s Self-Regulatory](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/)

Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising by visiting the opt-out pages on the NAI websites and [DAA websites](https://optout.aboutads.info/#!/). Opting out may make the ads you see across the internet less relevant to you.

If you have [opted out](https://adssettings.google.com/u/0/authenticated?hl=en) of receiving communications from us, we will not use your email for interest-based advertising.

#### How to Contact Us

If you have any questions about the use of your personal information, please email [privacy@adsrsounds.com](mailto:privacy@adsrsounds.com).  
Unless otherwise stated, ADSR Ltd is a data controller for personal data we collect through the ADSR Products and Services subject to this Privacy Statement and can be contacted via email at [privacy@adsrsounds.com](mailto:privacy@adsrsounds.com).

#### Changes to Our Privacy Statement

ADSR may modify or update this Statement when necessary, to reflect customer feedback and changes in our ADSR Products and Service. Please review it regularly. When we update this Statement, we will revise the ‘Last Update’ date at the top of the Statement. If there are material changes to the Statement or in how ADSR uses your personal data, we will inform you either by posting a notice of such changes, prior to them taking place, or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to regularly review this Statement to learn more how ADSR is using and protecting your information.

#### FAQ

The following are basic questions you may have about our privacy statement. We recommend that you read the detailed statement above for additional details.

WHY IS ADSR UPDATING ITS PRIVACY STATEMENT?   
We now meet the high standards required by the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and have updated our privacy statement to reflect that. We also strive to simplify language and remove jargon, to make our privacy statement easier to read and understand.

WHAT IS THE GDPR?   
The GDPR is a regulation intended to strengthen and unify data protection for everyone within the European Union (EU). As we believe that all our customers can benefit from its mandates, we’re implementing it globally. The GDPR requires greater openness and transparency from companies on how they collect, store and use personal data, while also imposing tighter limits on the use of personal data. You can learn more here.

HOW OFTEN DO YOU ANTICIPATE UPDATING YOUR PRIVACY STATEMENT?   
We will update our privacy statement as necessary to ensure that our policies are in line with international regulations, our product and business practices.

WHAT INFORMATION DOES ADSR COLLECT ABOUT ME?   
ADSR collects your name, phone number, email address, delivery address, location data, IP address, social identifiers, data provided by cookies and other similar technologies and functional data such as registration and system data,.

WHY DOES ADSR NEED MY INFORMATION?   
ADSR uses data to provide you with the best experience from the products and services we offer, which includes using data to improve and personalise your experiences. We also use data to communicate with you, for example, informing you about your account, new products or services available, security and other types of updates.

HOW IS MY INFORMATION USED?   
ADSR uses data for the following purposes:

  * Product Improvement
  * Future Product Development
  * Customer Support
  * Security, Safety, and Dispute Resolution
  * Product Performance Analysis
  * Communication and Marketing

HOW DOES COLLECTING MY INFORMATION HELP ADSR IMPROVE ITS PRODUCTS?   
We use the information for product and to make sure that we are offering you the best service options. We also collect error reports, so that we can make improvements to eliminate potential bugs and problems.

DOES ADSR SELL INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES?   
No. We never have. And we never will.

CAN I OPT OUT OF SHARING MY INFORMATION WITH ADSR?  
Yes, you can opt out of submitting certain types of personal information to ADSR, for instance, wishlists and other optional account information. Certain types of data that we collect are a necessity in order for the ADSR site and your products to perform their basic functions in a secure way and you will not be able to opt out from this data collection, sharing and/or processing.

HOW DO I DELETE MY PERSONAL DATA FROM ADSR AND WHAT ARE THE CONSEQUENCES?  
You can always send us an email via [privacy@adsrsounds.com](mailto:privacy@adsrsounds.com) or contact our Customer Care team and request that your data be deleted. Please note, however, that by deleting your personal data some features and services linked to your ADSR account such as any subscriptions will stop working.

DOES ADSR KEEP OR SHARE MY CREDIT CARD INFORMATION?  
No. All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers. ADSR uses Stripe to process our credit card payments and no credit card details are stored on our servers. Stripe has been audited by a PCI-certified auditor, and is certified to [PCI Service Provider Level 1](https://stripe.com/docs/security). This is the most stringent level of certification available.

HOW LONG DOES ADSR KEEP MY INFORMATION?  
ADSR retains personal data for as long as necessary to provide Services, support your Product and fulfill transactions you have requested, or for other essential purposes such as complying with our legal obligations, and resolving disputes and enforcing our agreements. Because these needs can vary for different data types in the context of different Products or Services, actual retention periods can vary significantly. For example, we will keep all functional data on file as long as you have an active ADSR account.

HOW IS INFORMATION STORED AND SECURED ON ADSR’S SERVERS?  
ADSR is committed to protecting the security of your personal data. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal data from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. For example, we store the personal data you provide on computer systems that have limited access and are in controlled facilities. Any data we transmit over the internet is protected using encryption.

IS ADSR USING COOKIES OR PIXELS TO GATHER INFORMATION?  
We use cookies and other similar technologies like pixels, tags and web beacons when you visit our website or use our App. By visiting our website or using our app, you agree to the use of cookies and similar technologies for the purposes described in our privacy statement. This helps us to provide you with the best experience and allows certain parts of our website to function properly. You can always adjust your browser or device settings to not accept cookies and similar technologies if this concerns you.

DOES ADSR USE INTEREST-BASED ADVERTISING?  
Yes. We work with third-party advertisers that utilise cookies and similar technologies to provide more relevant advertising about ADSR on our website and across the internet. To provide interest-based advertising, advertisers combine non-personal data obtained about your online activities over time to customise the advertising delivered to you. We do not share your personal information to do this.

WHAT SAFEGUARDS ARE IN PLACE FOR CHILDREN WHO HAVE ACCESS TO ADSR PRODUCTS?  
ADSR does not target and is not intended to attract children. ADSR does not knowingly solicit personal information from children or send them requests for personal information. Although visitors of all ages may navigate through our website, we do not intentionally collect personal information from those under the age of sixteen. If, following a notification by a parent or guardian, or discovery by other means, a child under sixteen has been improperly registered on this site by using false information, we will cancel the child’s account and delete the child’s personal information from our records.

HOW CAN I CONTACT ADSR IF I HAVE QUESTIONS REGARDING ADSR’S PRIVACY STATEMENT?  
If you have any questions about the use of your personal information, please send us an email to [privacy@adsrsounds.com](mailto:privacy@adsrsounds.com).
